<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Ahmed Mohammed | AI/ML Engineer</title><link>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Ahmed Mohammed | AI/ML Engineer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unlocking the MCP Model Context Protocol: Your Roadmap to Seamless Contextual Communication</title><link>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/mcp-model-context-protocol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/mcp-model-context-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="your-roadmap-to-seamless-contextual-communication">Your Roadmap to Seamless Contextual Communication&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hey there, tech trailblazers! 👋&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever wondered how modern systems keep their conversations in check, ensuring that every component &amp;ldquo;gets&amp;rdquo; the context it needs to function smoothly? Enter the MCP Model Context Protocol—a framework designed to keep data exchange smart, relevant, and super efficient. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and break it down!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-the-mcp-model-context-protocol">What Is the MCP Model Context Protocol?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Imagine a bustling conference call where every participant is in sync, sharing the right details at the right time. The MCP Model Context Protocol works just like that—but for systems. It&amp;rsquo;s a set of guidelines that enables different models and applications to exchange contextual information seamlessly. This means your apps aren&amp;rsquo;t just spitting out data; they&amp;rsquo;re engaging in meaningful, context-aware conversations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with AI and Machine Learning</title><link>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/first-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/first-post/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="getting-started-with-ai-and-machine-learning">Getting Started with AI and Machine Learning&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning are rapidly evolving fields that are transforming industries across the globe. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some insights for beginners looking to enter this exciting domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-machine-learning">What is Machine Learning?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Machine Learning is a subset of AI that enables computers to learn from data without being explicitly programmed. Instead of writing code that follows specific instructions to accomplish a task, you train a model on examples, and the model learns patterns from the data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Overview of Computer Vision Techniques</title><link>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/computer-vision-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/computer-vision-overview/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="an-overview-of-computer-vision-techniques">An Overview of Computer Vision Techniques&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Computer vision enables machines to &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; and interpret the visual world. As one of the most exciting areas of AI, it&amp;rsquo;s transforming industries from healthcare to autonomous vehicles.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fundamental-techniques">Fundamental Techniques&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Several key techniques form the foundation of computer vision:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="image-classification">Image Classification&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Image classification involves categorizing an image into one of several predefined classes. Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) have revolutionized this task, with architectures like ResNet, VGG, and EfficientNet pushing the boundaries of accuracy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your 5-Month LLM Adventure: From Zero to AI Whisperer</title><link>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/5-month-llm-adventure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ahmed-3m.github.io/blogs/5-month-llm-adventure/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="your-5-month-llm-adventure-from-zero-to-ai-whisperer">Your 5-Month LLM Adventure: From Zero to AI Whisperer&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hey there, future AI whisperer! 👋&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard the buzz about Large Language Models (LLMs) – things like ChatGPT, Gemini, Claude – and you&amp;rsquo;re thinking, &amp;ldquo;How does that magic actually work? And could I learn it?&amp;rdquo; The answer is a resounding &amp;ldquo;YES&amp;rdquo;, but like any epic question, it requires a map.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forget dense textbooks for a moment. This is your 5-month, down-to-earth guide to understanding, using, and maybe even building with LLMs. It&amp;rsquo;s intense, but totally doable. Ready? Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>